[{"question": "Asks for experiences with financing options such as FutureFamily, Lending Club, and CapexMD for IVF costs.", "answer": "One suggestion is to consider using a credit card with a great sign-up bonus, travel points, cashback, or a 0% introductory offer for financing IVF costs if able to pay off immediately.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1b3honm/financing/", "score": 1}, {"question": "Asks for options to afford a $16,900 IVF cycle upfront.", "answer": "Options include opening a new credit card with 0% APR, applying for personal loans, seeking grants, or fertility-specific personal loans. It is advised to have a budget and plan in place as costs may exceed the initial amount. Additionally, it is recommended to inquire about the number of cycles included in the price.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/18rj1ca/ivf_discount_and_financing/", "score": 1}, {"question": "Asks for recommendations on credit cards for paying out-of-pocket IVF costs, preferably with benefits for hitting a certain spending target.", "answer": "Some suggested credit cards for general cash back include Chase Freedom Unlimited, Chase Sapphire Preferred, and Discover IT cash back. Specific options include the Amazon Chase Credit Card for Amazon/WF purchases and the Marriott Bonvoy Amex for travel-related points. Another option used by a commenter is a Capital One card offering 0% for 18 months.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/193gtuz/credit_cards_financing/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Asks for experiences with financing IVF cycles through Ally, lending club, or Future family, or alternative financing options.", "answer": "Some individuals have taken out loans from credit unions, with better interest rates available when using collateral such as vehicles or a house.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/17kbw7q/financing/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Inquires about recommendations for finance companies to cover the costs of IVF treatment.", "answer": "Suggestion to consider 0% interest credit cards that offer a period without interest, providing a potential financial solution for IVF expenses.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/174pdsv/opinions_on_finance_lenders/", "score": 3}, {"question": "Asks for creative ways of funding IVF treatment due to sticker shock.", "answer": "Suggestions include finding a job with fertility benefits, exploring lower-cost clinics like CNY, taking out a loan, and checking for insurance coverage for IVF.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/12tjle5/finances/", "score": 1}, {"question": "Concerns about insurance coverage for IVF treatments after reaching the maximum allowed rounds, specifically regarding FETs.", "answer": "Some clinics may not be proactive in navigating insurance coverage, requiring patients to verify and clarify coverage themselves. Patients may need to contact their insurance directly to resolve discrepancies and ensure accurate coverage for IVF treatments.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/16hb015/finances_and_insurance_coverage/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Asks for advice on whether to switch back to Gonal F and Luveris from Pergoveris to save \u00a3200 per round, considering the subjective value of the savings compared to the overall costs of IVF.", "answer": "A commenter recommends sticking with Pergoveris for potentially better results with fewer side effects, especially for those with Diminished Ovarian Reserve (DOR).", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/17r9vxu/pergoveris_advice_finance_question_uk_based/", "score": 1}, {"question": "Inquires about experiences, reviews, and opinions on financing options for IVF, particularly in Central California.", "answer": "One comment suggests specifying the location for more tailored responses.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/12jrwqm/financing/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Asks how people financed multiple IVF cycles and if they set limitations on attempts.", "answer": "Some relied on insurance coverage to afford IVF, while others used personal loans, cash, second mortgages, 401K loans, or took on part-time jobs to cover costs. Setting limitations on attempts varied among individuals based on financial resources and circumstances.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/zpu8lq/financing/", "score": 4}, {"question": "Inquires about recent interest rates for loans related to IVF financing.", "answer": "One individual shared getting a 0% interest rate for 2 years on their loan in March 2022 at their clinic.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/15lsvmm/interest_rates_when_financing/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Asks for recommendations and experiences with IVF financing companies like Future Family.", "answer": "No comments provided for recommendations or experiences with IVF financing companies.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/13qjdkm/ivf_financing_recommendations/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Asks for advice on financing options for IVF, considering options like HELOC, credit cards, personal loans, and a specific company called Future Family.", "answer": "Comments suggest avoiding high-rate fertility financing companies, considering personal loans with lower rates (around 5.25%), utilizing 0% credit cards for financing, exploring HELOC for better rates, and looking into programs like Progyny through employers like Amazon for IVF coverage.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/qrqt8s/financing_for_ivf/", "score": 3}, {"question": "Asks if there are options for IVF financing with 0% interest for a period like 1 or 2 years.", "answer": "Some individuals have found 0% interest credit card options for 18 months or longer through their banks, with the possibility of extending the interest-free period by making timely payments.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/v7an9c/ivf_financing_0_anyone/", "score": 4}, {"question": "Inquires about financing options for IVF, particularly for families with one income.", "answer": "Suggestions include exploring part-time job options at companies with good infertility benefits, considering job opportunities with infertility coverage, applying for infertility financial support from clinics, utilizing rewards credit cards for cash back, negotiating discounts with doctors, and exploring external financing options such as BetterMed for lower interest rates and flexible payment plans.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/gdkpys/financing_ivf/", "score": 18}, {"question": "Inquires about the additional costs for a frozen embryo transfer at CNY clinic, including medication expenses.", "answer": "Frozen embryo transfer at CNY costs $1095 each, including a $150 fee and potential discounts for upfront payment. Medication costs are not included, but some individuals have insurance coverage for medications. Additional costs include blood draw charges of $100 per visit.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1aoboyq/question_for_those_who_have_financed_with_cny/", "score": 1}, {"question": "Asks for advice on choosing between different ARC Fertility financing packages, specifically regarding the ability to \"bank\" embryos and potential refunds for unused procedures.", "answer": "One commenter recommends opting for the 3-cycle package to try and bank embryos, especially considering age-related factors and the importance of time in their case. They shared a personal experience of sending embryos for testing which came back abnormal, emphasizing the emotional difficulty of the process.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/xeg4f8/arc_financing_plans_advice/", "score": 1}, {"question": "Asks for recommendations on personal loans for IVF financing with fair credit.", "answer": "Comment suggests looking into CapexMD as a potential option for financing IVF with fair credit.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/x1w83v/financing/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Inquires about IVF financing companies offering no interest for the first few months.", "answer": "Fertility loans may have high rates, so contacting the clinic for partnerships with banks or in-house financing options is suggested. Alternatively, using a zero-interest credit card with rewards is a commonly recommended option.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/16cm3ys/any_ivf_financing_companies_offer_no_interest_for/", "score": 1}, {"question": "Asks for advice on creating an IVF Finance and Insurance Reform Coalition to address the financial and insurance challenges in the IVF process in the USA.", "answer": "The user is passionate about establishing a platform for those facing finance and insurance hurdles in IVF. They aim to gather stories, bring in medical expertise, and present sound medical justifications to policymakers in each state to advocate for insurance reform for IVF. The user also shares a personal experience with insurance company challenges in covering prescribed medication for IVF.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/uj37wm/ivf_financing_and_insurance_reform_coalition/", "score": 7}, {"question": "Inquires about experiences with IVF treatment financing, including how to find a provider, potential pitfalls, and recommendations.", "answer": "Consider borrowing against a 401k for IVF financing as it can be easy and the interest paid goes towards the balance, though potential downside includes missing out on investment gains. Other options include using 0% credit cards with a 24-month payoff period or seeking discounts for payment by check instead of credit card.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/j7kz89/ivf_financing/", "score": 7}, {"question": "Inquires about the ease of working with CapexMD, LLC for IVF financing and their timeliness in responding.", "answer": "Commenters have mentioned that CapexMD is great to work with, sends money directly to clinics and testing facilities, and suggest asking for more than the expected amount needed.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/jfjiy2/capexmd_llc_financing/", "score": 7}, {"question": "Inquires about the possibility of IVF loans covering medication costs.", "answer": "IVF loans can cover various expenses including medications. Some individuals have had success with IVF loans that covered costs such as stims, egg retrieval, freezing, PGS, FET, and medications. Additionally, borrowing from a 401K was another option for some, with interest paid back into the retirement account.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/mx81z2/does_anyone_have_experience_with_financing_ivf/", "score": 3}, {"question": "Asks for experiences and advice on using ARC Fertility packages and financing for IVF cycles.", "answer": "A commenter suggests using WINfertility as an alternative provider that is deemed to be pretty good.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/ibop97/arc_fertility_packages_financing/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Asks for experiences with ARC Fertility for financing IVF treatments.", "answer": "One commenter recommends using a 0% interest credit card for 18 months for financing and, if needed, taking a loan from their 401k to avoid paying interest to external lenders.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/nsdwbe/anyone_have_experience_with_arc_fertility_for/", "score": 3}, {"question": "Asks fellow IVFers about their occupations to afford expensive treatments and medications.", "answer": "Responses include various professions such as lawyer, pharmacist, engineer, public school teacher, accountant, tech support manager, therapist, and software engineer. Some have benefits covering IVF, while others rely on savings, insurance, or out-of-pocket payments. Strategies include using employer-provided benefits, government subsidies, loans, credit cards, and savings.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/15lyav4/what_is_your_occupation/", "score": 35}, {"question": "Asks for advice on low-cost options for IVF after experiencing multiple losses due to egg quality issues.", "answer": "Commenters suggest considering IVF clinics in Mexico, such as Ingenes in Tijuana, which offer more affordable packages with potential refund guarantees. They also recommend exploring options for discounted medications in Mexico and utilizing monitoring services in the US to reduce costs. Additionally, genetic testing is advised as a worthwhile investment given the circumstances.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/19feuf6/new_here_need_advice_for_lowcost_options_after_5/", "score": 4}, {"question": "Asks for opinions on whether to opt for PGT testing during IVF, considering additional cost and success rates.", "answer": "Comments suggest that PGT testing can be beneficial for reducing chances of implantation failure or miscarriage, but it's a personal decision based on individual circumstances such as age, history of recurrent pregnancy loss, and financial considerations. Some found it worth the cost for the information and increased chances of success, while others opted out due to financial constraints.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/149nl5m/to_pgt_or_not_to_pgt/", "score": 5}, {"question": "Asks for advice on whether to opt for PGT-A testing during IVF, given DOR and personal circumstances.", "answer": "Comments suggest testing for PGT-A to potentially avoid heartbreaks later, reduce stress and miscarriage rates, and maximize chances of successful transfers. Some individuals shared personal experiences of testing and the benefits it brought in terms of embryo viability and reducing the emotional and financial burden of failed transfers.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/zefmip/cannot_decide_on_pgta_testing/", "score": 12}, {"question": "Inquires about the cost of IVF treatment for individuals with PCOS who are considering the IVF route.", "answer": "Costs range from $13,000 to $53,000+ per cycle, excluding medications and additional testing. Some individuals opt for shared risk programs or financing options. Checking insurance coverage is recommended, as some states mandate fertility coverage.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/16jplcm/what_was_the_cost_of_your_ivf/", "score": 18}, {"question": "Expresses discouragement due to the high cost of IVF medications, despite having financing options.", "answer": "Some individuals have used credit cards with 0% interest to finance IVF medications. Others have found more affordable options by shopping around for medications at different pharmacies or using specialized pharmacies like IVF Smart. The financial burden of IVF can be overwhelming, especially when insurance coverage is limited. The lack of affordable healthcare options in the USA adds to the stress and frustration of the situation.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/14egpjp/discouraged/", "score": 11}, {"question": "Should the individual transfer the one normal embryo or go through another round of IVF to potentially obtain more embryos, considering factors like age, finances, and chances of success?", "answer": "Opinions vary, with some suggesting transferring the embryo if only one child is desired, while others recommend another egg retrieval to bank more embryos if multiple children are desired. Factors such as age, previous experiences, and personal goals should be considered when making this decision.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/16y8o36/one_normal_embryo/", "score": 27}, {"question": "Inquires about the number of FETs without a live birth and if it's worth continuing given the financial and emotional toll.", "answer": "Some individuals have undergone up to 12 FETs with varying outcomes, including miscarriages and unsuccessful transfers. Research suggests chances of live birth improve up to 9 cycles. Many express emotional exhaustion and frustration with the ongoing process, highlighting the toll it takes on finances and mental health.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/17a150a/do_you_hold_the_record_over_of_fets_with_no_live/", "score": 83}, {"question": "Inquires about IVF clinics that do not have BMI restrictions for treatment.", "answer": "A commenter mentioned Chicago IVF as a clinic that does not mention or enforce BMI restrictions for treatment.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1b2mw9b/any_bmi_no_rule_clinic/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Asks about the possibility of getting pregnant without fallopian tubes and the costs and outcomes of IVF for such cases.", "answer": "IVF is a viable option for individuals without fallopian tubes. Costs in the U.S. vary, with expenses for egg retrieval, medications, and frozen embryo transfers. Success rates may vary, and additional attempts may be necessary. Some individuals have had portions of their IVF costs covered by insurance, but out-of-pocket expenses can still be significant. It is recommended to consider all options and seek advice from a fertility clinic.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1au4q7j/pregnancy_without_fallopian_tubes/", "score": 9}, {"question": "Asks for advice on whether to proceed with IVF now or wait to buy a house first, considering financial implications and fertility concerns.", "answer": "Comments suggest considering job opportunities with fertility coverage, exploring overseas options for cheaper IVF, borrowing from a 401k or using 0% interest credit cards for financing, buying a house with income potential, looking into state programs for first-time homebuyers, and prioritizing IVF due to limited fertility window.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/wgwefo/what_would_you_do_financial_question/", "score": 11}, {"question": "Expresses feeling guilty for sharing financial struggles related to IVF with a friend who may not fully understand the complexities and costs involved.", "answer": "Comments suggest that not everyone will understand the physical, mental, emotional, and financial toll of IVF. Some friends may not grasp the uncertainties and sacrifices involved, leading to potential strain on relationships. It's important to prioritize self-care and surround oneself with understanding individuals during the IVF journey.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1azyfsb/friend_upset_with_me/", "score": 13}, {"question": "Asks for recommendations on less expensive pharmacies for IVF medication, considering paying out of pocket to avoid hitting insurance lifetime maximum.", "answer": "Some recommended pharmacies include Freedom Fertility, Schraft's 2.0, and Alto, which offer competitive pricing and convenient services like same-day delivery and easy online ordering.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/y2m76d/pharmacy_recommendations_for_medication/", "score": 4}, {"question": "Asks for advice on affording IVF, particularly IVF with embryo testing, given the high cost and anxiety about potential unsuccessful outcomes.", "answer": "Some individuals opt for cheaper clinics that offer financing options. It may be possible to save up for different stages of IVF treatment, such as egg retrieval and transfers, rather than paying the full amount upfront.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/17patqz/how_do_i_afford_ivf/", "score": 3}, {"question": "Asks if an egg retrieval and a frozen embryo transfer can be done on the same day to potentially save money on IVF costs.", "answer": "It is not ethically or medically advisable to do an egg retrieval and a transfer on the same day. The timing of the egg retrieval is crucial for success and combining it with a transfer could result in poor outcomes. Additionally, without proper stimulation, the likelihood of obtaining mature eggs for transfer is low.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/191dn3j/random_question_could_an_egg_retrieval_and_a/", "score": 0}, {"question": "Asks about experiences with supplemental fertility insurance, including details on monthly premiums and whether it needs to be from the same company as primary health insurance.", "answer": "Some express frustration at the lack of coverage in state plans, highlighting the financial burden of IVF without insurance assistance.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/18yv5oe/supplemental_fertility_insurance_experience/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Asks for advice on whether to continue freezing eggs or switch to freezing embryos, given a low egg yield and future plans to use them with a future partner.", "answer": "Comments suggest considering freezing both eggs and embryos if multiple cycles are affordable. Embryos have higher success rates and provide more information on fertilization and embryo development, while eggs have more future options but more unknowns. Freezing embryos can provide useful insights and increase the odds of a successful live birth. It's advised to keep collecting eggs and consider embryo storage for better outcomes.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/16qzzq6/egg_freezing_dilemma/", "score": 15}, {"question": "Asks for guidance on coping with the emotional toll of failed IVF attempts and the isolation felt during the process.", "answer": "Commenters offer support and share their own experiences of heartbreak, isolation, and eventual success in IVF journeys. They emphasize the importance of being kind to oneself, seeking support from experienced counselors with fertility knowledge, and shifting the focus from having a child to doing the best possible with available resources.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/18jpwpp/never_felt_more_alone/", "score": 17}, {"question": "Expresses frustration and emotional pain after multiple failed IVF transfers, miscarriage, and physical complications.", "answer": "Comments offer empathy and support, reminding the OP that infertility is not a judgment but a difficult journey. Encouragement to be kind to oneself and not give up hope is shared, along with well wishes for a successful outcome in the future.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/18nqdll/this_has_been_a_cruel_journey_for_me/", "score": 43}, {"question": "Inquires about the experience with Future Family's 0% interest loan and fertility coaching membership for IVF financing.", "answer": "One user finds the program a good option compared to their clinic's financing. Another suggests exploring 0% interest personal loans from credit card companies as an alternative option.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/10j4mjp/future_family_membership/", "score": 3}, {"question": "Inquires about tips for being a travel patient at CNY Buffalo clinic, located 6 hours away, and planning to do most procedures remotely.", "answer": "Another user mentions positive feedback about CNY Buffalo clinic and expresses hopes for a successful next cycle. No specific tips or tricks are provided in the comments.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/18um09s/on_to_the_next_clinic/", "score": 5}, {"question": "Asks for advice on when to start IVF considering financial concerns and age (31 turning 32 soon) after experiencing fertility issues.", "answer": "Comment suggests starting IVF sooner than desired, as waiting might lead to regret. Personal experience shared regrets over delaying IVF by a year.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1bima82/any_advice_on_when_to_start_ivf/", "score": 1}, {"question": "Asks whether to save money for the transfer or pay for another vial of sperm as a back-up plan for future use.", "answer": "Comment suggests considering purchasing another vial of sperm as a precaution, as running out of donor sperm can be a significant setback.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1be1098/to_buy_or_not_to_buy/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Asks about the average number of frozen embryo transfers (FETs) typically needed before achieving pregnancy/live birth.", "answer": "Some sources suggest that around 95% of people may achieve pregnancy with 3 FETs of euploid embryos, but this can vary based on individual factors. Studies show that for women under 37 without recurrent pregnancy loss, the average number of transfers to live birth was 1.3. Lack of testing options can make the process more challenging, and it may be beneficial to explore alternative tests like endometrial biopsy or laparoscopy if available. Personal experiences vary, with some individuals needing more transfers before achieving a successful pregnancy.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/186a7pw/what_is_the_average_number_of_fets_failed_fet/", "score": 13}, {"question": "Asks for advice on managing stress during IVF while working as a teacher, particularly in an anxiety-inducing environment.", "answer": "Comments share experiences of leaving teaching to focus on IVF due to stress and lack of support from schools. Some teachers used sick time for IVF, faced judgment from colleagues, and struggled with balancing work and self-care. Stressful work environments during IVF treatment were reported to impact pregnancy outcomes.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/15wi5yr/quit_teaching_during_ivf/", "score": 8}, {"question": "Asks for advice on whether to continue with IVF after two failed FETs and considering factors like age, financial strain, and emotional toll.", "answer": "Comments suggest considering factors such as affordability, age, number of transfers, and personal desires. Encouragement to give it another try due to statistical average for success after three transfers, while also acknowledging the emotional and physical challenges involved.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/18ztizb/2nd_fet_failed_give_up_or_try_again/", "score": 4}, {"question": "Expresses disappointment and financial concerns after a failed first egg retrieval.", "answer": "Considering scraping funds together for another cycle on credit cards, but worries about repayment. Clinic recommends frozen transfer due to complications. Limited by finances, feeling devastated about the possibility of not being able to afford further attempts. Asking for words of support.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1bkzkin/first_er_was_a_bust/", "score": 11}, {"question": "Seeks guidance on dealing with denied claims through Winfertility, with confusion and blame-shifting between the clinic, Winfertility, and insurance providers.", "answer": "It is suggested to ensure the clinic submits the correct forms to Winfertility, as this can lead to backdated approvals. Persistence in contacting all parties involved is key to resolving issues with denied claims.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/16menmb/winfertility_and_denied_claims/", "score": 1}, {"question": "Asks for good prices for IVF in the US without considering insurance coverage.", "answer": "University of VT Medical Center offered IVF for $6995 including meds, transfer, and monitoring in 2016. CNY currently offers IVF for $5000 including ICSI, monitoring, transfer, and storage for a year, but does not include meds and extras. They have multiple locations and offer financing options with high acceptance rates. The post also inquires about the process of monitoring at a home clinic while receiving treatment at CNY.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/r3m4s4/good_prices_for_ivf_in_us/", "score": 30}, {"question": "Asks for insights and experiences with IVF clinics Poma and SRM, as well as average costs of an IVF cycle.", "answer": "Average costs of an IVF cycle can range from $20,000 to $25,000. Breakdown includes IVF meds ($5,000), egg retrieval ($12,000), anesthesia ($1,450), ICSI ($1,500), PGT testing ($5,000), and donor sperm ($500-$1,000 if applicable).", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1b7rc5j/poma_vs_srm/", "score": 1}, {"question": "Inquires about discount programs for IVF injectable medications for low-income families.", "answer": "Suggested reaching out to the clinic's financial coordinator or billing department, as they may have relationships with pharmacies that offer discounts on medications.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/175haox/ivf_drug_discount_programs/", "score": 3}, {"question": "Asks for advice on what to ask for in the next IVF attempt after multiple failed FETs.", "answer": "Suggestions include seeking counseling for emotional support, considering changing clinics for a fresh perspective, and trying different self-care routines to cope with the emotional rollercoaster.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/17ux0pd/another_failed_fetim_broken/", "score": 18}, {"question": "Expresses uncertainty about using donor eggs with her husband's sperm due to relationship issues and legal barriers in India.", "answer": "Comments advise against reconciling with a partner who shows no support, financial stability, or willingness to have a child. Suggestions include seeking counseling, prioritizing mental well-being, considering embryo adoption or adoption in the future, and carefully evaluating the decision to proceed with IVF in such circumstances.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/191gefp/embryo_or_just_eggs_donation/", "score": 9}, {"question": "Asks about the standard number of IVF rounds before achieving a positive pregnancy test, especially for a 24-year-old with a history of miscarriages.", "answer": "The number of IVF rounds varies for each individual based on factors like age and infertility diagnosis. It is different for everyone, and support and prayers are extended to those going through fertility treatments.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1almo7v/how_many_ivf_rounds_are_standard/", "score": 1}, {"question": "Asks for a summary of the cost of IVF in Mexico.", "answer": "The clinic in Mexico is offering financing options, making IVF more affordable. They are also hosting a free online event to discuss IVF costs and information.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1bi0924/ivf_in_mexico/", "score": 6}, {"question": "Seeks clarity on coverage for IVF under the Medica Elect/Essential plan through the University of Minnesota, specifically regarding the annual maximum of $5,000 for fertility treatments.", "answer": "The definition of \"fertility treatment\" and what expenses count towards the $5,000 limit is unclear. Seeking guidance from the Minnesota Infertility group on Facebook may provide more insight and personal experiences with navigating IVF under this specific insurance plan.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1adfy4g/help_with_medica_insurance_from_the_university_of/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Asks if it's possible to use an ARC fertility bundle for back-to-back retrievals without transferring embryos from the first cycle.", "answer": "It's unclear if back-to-back retrievals are allowed with ARC bundles. Concerns include potential financial loss if not all retrievals are completed due to health reasons or other factors. Lack of detailed cost estimates from the clinic adds to the uncertainty.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1b54guq/arc_fertility_bundling_question/", "score": 1}, {"question": "Inquires about the possibility of success in IVF after experiencing multiple failed attempts.", "answer": "Success is possible even after multiple failed attempts, with factors like PGT testing of embryos and age influencing success rates.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/18x9csv/anyone_have_success_on_second_or_third_try/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Inquires about the cost estimates for embryo transfer and PGTa testing in IVF treatment, considering whether to pay as they go or finance.", "answer": "Estimated costs provided by comments are around $4-$6k for embryo transfer, $1200 for biopsy per retrieval, and $2800 for testing per batch. Some individuals opt for 0% APR credit cards for financing.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/154s7mo/pay_as_you_go_cost_estimates/", "score": 1}, {"question": "Seeks recommendations for IVF fertility clinics in Nevada or surrounding areas due to negative experiences with current clinic staff.", "answer": "Some users suggest considering smaller clinics not part of a chain, where they have had positive experiences with easy appointment scheduling and friendly staff.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1awi2f6/any_good_recommendations_for_ivf_fertility/", "score": 4}, {"question": "Asks for recommendations on doctors in the Midwest with high SART scoring for IVF treatments.", "answer": "One commenter recommends the Cleveland Clinic in the Midwest, praising the doctors, nurses, and staff.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/15r467n/midwest_doctors/", "score": 1}, {"question": "Expresses heartbreak over IVF failure due to egg quality issues and financial constraints. Seeks advice on affordable options for future attempts.", "answer": "Some suggest considering more affordable clinics like CNY, exploring job options with fertility benefits, or utilizing resources like Aimee Raupp's egg quality diet. Additionally, there are suggestions for obtaining insurance coverage for additional IVF cycles in the US. Others share personal experiences of successful outcomes despite initial egg degeneration issues, emphasizing the importance of considering individual responses to medications and potential overstimulation.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/17xz6qa/its_over/", "score": 85}, {"question": "Asks for key questions to ask during a consultation before starting another IVF retrieval cycle, particularly focused on improving chances given issues with egg quality.", "answer": "It is suggested to have a realistic discussion about the odds of success to manage expectations effectively.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/18dng8a/if_you_could_ask_anything/", "score": 3}, {"question": "Seeks support and encouragement after experiencing a reduction in the number of embryos post-egg retrieval, with concerns about the potential for blastocyst formation and future rounds of IVF due to financial constraints.", "answer": "Comments suggest that experiencing a decrease in the number of embryos post-retrieval is common, with attrition rates of 70-80%. Encouragement is given regarding the normal trajectory of the situation, and reassurance is provided that the individual is on track despite feeling anxious.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1bq1ac1/er_yesterday/", "score": 6}, {"question": "Asks if it is common practice for clinics to charge for procedures like biopsy, freezing, and storage even if no embryos make it to the biopsy stage during IVF.", "answer": "Some clinics may charge for such procedures in advance, even if no embryos are produced. Patients may need to be persistent in demanding refunds and may have to escalate to speaking to the head of billing to resolve billing discrepancies.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1aegnts/billing_issues_rant/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Asks for opinions on whether to PGS test embryos in IVF, considering factors such as cost and potential benefits.", "answer": "Commenters provide varying perspectives based on personal experiences. Some highlight the potential benefits of PGS testing in identifying abnormal embryos to prevent miscarriages, while others express concerns about potential risks and limitations of the testing. Ultimately, the decision to undergo PGS testing depends on individual preferences, risk tolerance, and financial considerations.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/owjwnp/to_pgs_test_or_not/", "score": 11}, {"question": "Inquires about the experience of taking out a loan to cover IVF costs and asks for recommendations on where to get the loan.", "answer": "Some individuals have successfully used personal loans from banks like Suntrust's Lightstream or interest-free credit cards to cover IVF costs. The process was reported as easy and quick.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/159bd9m/loan_for_ivf_help/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Asks for advice on when to consider moving on from IVF after multiple unsuccessful rounds and no euploid embryos.", "answer": "Some individuals have experienced success with euploid embryos in future rounds of IVF after multiple unsuccessful attempts. It is noted that the process can be emotionally challenging, and some find it helpful to view it as an expensive hobby to alleviate some pressure. Additionally, there is a mention of using Omnitrope as a consideration in the process.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/16mdp5a/advice_on_when_to_move_on_40f_four_ers_zero/", "score": 10}, {"question": "Inquires about delaying IVF treatment due to insurance clearance issues and potential impact on medication effectiveness.", "answer": "Comment suggests coming in on Monday to talk to the finance department before the appointment to make an informed decision about delaying treatment.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/114dsl8/would_you_delay/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Seeks recommendations for financing options for IVF using donor eggs after exhausting insurance coverage.", "answer": "Changing jobs to access additional fertility benefits, such as Progyny, which may cover donor eggs, is suggested. Inquire about fertility-focused personal loans from the clinic.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/xuw49l/used_up_all_my_ivf_benefits_whats_next/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Asks about the frequency of acupuncture sessions prior to FET and if it helped.", "answer": "Some recommend 5-7 sessions of acupuncture once the medicated FET cycle begins. The acupuncturist may also provide treatment before and after the transfer at the clinic.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/188ows0/acupuncture_for_fet/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Asks for recommendations on companies offering pharmacy plans, IVF programs, or financing plans to make self-paying for IVF more financially manageable.", "answer": "One commenter suggested using Apthorp on the Upper West Side for cheaper medication costs, although it's uncertain if they offer payment plans.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/119yff2/self_pay_nyc/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Asks how others in a similar situation, where both partners are carriers for a genetic disorder, made decisions regarding IVF with PGT-M and how it impacted their timeline and finances.", "answer": "Some chose IVF with PGT-M as it was deemed more cost-effective than potential medical expenses for a child with the genetic disorder. Costs for IVF with PGT-M can vary, with one person mentioning roughly $12k out of pocket for the first round plus additional genetic testing. Timelines can involve a 6-month process before being ready to try to get pregnant, with waiting periods involved. Some individuals are also considering the option of making a PGTM probe before deciding on IVF.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/10js9a1/carriers_howwhy_did_you_choose_ivf_with_pgt_m_and/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Asks for advice on managing a partner with severe ADHD during fertility treatments, particularly when the partner seems distracted by job opportunities and instability.", "answer": "Commenters may suggest open communication about priorities and setting boundaries during the fertility journey. Seeking couples counseling or ADHD-specific support could also be beneficial in navigating through these challenges.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/17jigfe/adhd_fertility_journey/", "score": 3}, {"question": "Asks for success stories of transferring a 3BB embryo, particularly from older individuals.", "answer": "A commenter shared their experience of transferring a 3BB embryo and achieving positive betas and a home pregnancy test at 16 days post-transfer, offering hope and positivity to the original poster.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1as1k5e/any_success_stories_with_3bb_embryos/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Asks for advice on how to proceed after a disastrous first round of IVF, feeling angry and depressed about the outcome and unsure about continuing with a second round.", "answer": "Commenters suggest considering a different protocol, such as duo stim, to improve outcomes. They also recommend using medications to prevent early ovulation and seeking a second opinion from a different reproductive endocrinologist for a new course of action.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/13amwoo/ivf_disaster_first_round_why_keep_going/", "score": 12}, {"question": "Expresses deep frustration and jealousy towards others easily conceiving while struggling with infertility, particularly amidst family dynamics where irresponsible individuals seem to have no trouble getting pregnant.", "answer": "Commenters relate to the OP's feelings, sharing their own struggles and observations of seemingly irresponsible or dysfunctional individuals having no trouble conceiving, leading to feelings of unfairness and frustration. The lack of awareness and discussion around infertility issues, especially relating to conditions like endometriosis impacting fertility, is highlighted.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1aj1m1t/fuck_infertility/", "score": 159}, {"question": "Asks if there were other options after receiving devastating news during pregnancy.", "answer": "The post does not provide information on whether the couple explored other options or had to continue the pregnancy despite the devastating news.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/13jwieh/the_ivf_process_beginning_to_end/", "score": 231}, {"question": "Asks for advice on whether to do a second egg retrieval or transfer one embryo if interested in having a second child in the future.", "answer": "Suggestions include doing another retrieval for future options, trying one transfer first followed by a second retrieval if needed, considering the age factor for success rates, and exploring options based on personal preferences and circumstances.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/s351uv/poll_what_would_you_do/", "score": 4}, {"question": "Asks if Boston IVF allows patients to do back-to-back Egg Retrievals (ERs) in the IVF process.", "answer": "If using insurance, the finance team may delay the process, requiring patients to advocate for faster progress. Out-of-pocket payments might lead to a smoother process.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/17luj9l/does_boston_ivf_let_you_do_back_to_back_ers/", "score": 1}, {"question": "Asks for advice on using Fertility Access for financing IVF after multiple failed IUIs.", "answer": "A commenter recommends looking into WinFertility and suggests considering a loan through a 401k if available, as it may offer a better return on investment and help pay off the loan more effectively.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/ovk6gz/fertility_access_program_advice/", "score": 3}, {"question": "Expresses frustration over insurance issues causing a potential missed egg retrieval cycle due to denial and delays in approval.", "answer": "Commenters advise not giving up and recommend calling the clinic and insurance for expedited approval. Suggests that there may still be time to start the cycle even if the period arrives, and mentions the option of a mid-luteal start.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/17j763z/insurance_woes/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Asks about the average timeframe before starting IVF in different countries and the factors influencing that decision.", "answer": "In the USA, guidelines suggest 6 months of trying for those over 35 and 1 year for those under 35 before seeking fertility testing and treatment. The decision to proceed with IVF may vary based on personal choice, insurance coverage, and individual circumstances. Some individuals opt for IVF sooner to avoid wasting time, while others may face challenges with insurance coverage and waiting periods for treatment.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/147y5ih/after_how_many_years_did_you_start_ivf_what_is/", "score": 5}, {"question": "Can IVF-related procedures post-embryo creation be billed to the male partner's fertility insurance?", "answer": "Clinics may be reluctant to bill the male partner's insurance, requiring patients to generate invoices in their name and submit to the husband's insurance themselves. Some patients opt to exhaust their insurance coverage and switch to the husband's insurance for potentially broader coverage. It may be necessary to clarify with the clinic the process for billing the husband's insurance.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/12xh02m/charging_husbands_insurance/", "score": 4}, {"question": "Asks if the low maturity rate of eggs retrieved during IVF rounds speaks to egg quality.", "answer": "The low maturity rate may not necessarily indicate poor egg quality as it can be a variable factor in the IVF process. It is noted to be a challenging and unpredictable process, and being able to retrieve a certain number of eggs is still a positive outcome.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1anm6ez/third_round_results/", "score": 1}, {"question": "Asks for experiences and thoughts on declining genetic carrier screening and testing during IVF.", "answer": "Commenters shared various perspectives - some found peace of mind and valuable information through testing, others regretted not testing their embryos after a failed transfer, and some discovered they were carriers for genetic conditions. It was noted that knowledge is power, and genetic testing can provide reassurance and help in making informed decisions during the IVF process. Some mentioned successful cases where insurance covered the testing costs.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/18gvj3w/genetic_screening_for_ivf_has_anyone_regretted/", "score": 0}, {"question": "Expresses frustration and bitterness about the waiting and challenges of fertility treatments, particularly IVF, due to low ovarian reserve and male factor infertility.", "answer": "The comments provide support and understanding for the OP's feelings, acknowledging the struggles and disappointments faced during the IVF journey.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/14ub4of/im_tired_of_waiting_and_feeling_bitter/", "score": 65}, {"question": "Asks if anyone has undergone IVF after having their tubes removed and how many rounds were needed.", "answer": "One individual had two successful retrievals and a successful transfer after having their tubes removed. They had two unsuccessful retrievals prior, allowing the doctor to determine a suitable protocol.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/14xzals/ivf_after_total_tube_removal/", "score": 0}, {"question": "Asks for thoughts on whether to undergo egg retrieval soon due to lower AMH levels at age 30, considering financial constraints.", "answer": "Comment suggests that retrieving eggs sooner may lead to better outcomes due to higher quality and quantity when younger, as regret over delay in retrieval is expressed by a 35-year-old with lower AMH levels.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/15sg2zp/lower_amh_plans_for_future/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Expresses frustration at having to work overtime to fund IVF that should be covered by insurance.", "answer": "Some individuals opt for financing options like Future Family to cover the costs of IVF instead of working extensive overtime.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/11034f8/working_overtime_to_fund_ivf/", "score": 80}, {"question": "Seeks advice on choosing between a HDHP and an OAP plan for egg freezing considering the potential lack of coverage by Cigna insurance.", "answer": "Cigna may not cover egg freezing. It is suggested to review the fertility coverage in the policies, including lifetime maximums and medication coverage. Progyny is mentioned as a potential option for egg freezing coverage that companies can add as a benefit.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/17vb9tw/egg_freezingivf_hdhp_or_opa/", "score": 1}, {"question": "", "answer": "Asks for advice on dealing with a husband who keeps changing his mind about pursuing IVF and is not fully invested in having children.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/104c4r1/husband_wants_to_wait/", "score": 22}, {"question": "Asks for opinions on whether to bank or transfer frozen embryos after a failed fresh transfer, considering age and number of embryos.", "answer": "Comments suggest that reasons not to bank include financial concerns and not wanting more than one child. Some opt to bank for the security of having multiple embryos for future transfers. Insurance coverage may also impact the decision to bank or transfer.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/ur5o2y/is_there_any_reason_not_to_bank/", "score": 5}, {"question": "Expresses overwhelming emotions about starting IVF earlier than expected due to fertility issues and endometriosis, seeking support and advice.", "answer": "Encouragement to focus on one's unique journey, gather information from reliable sources like podcasts, and take the IVF process one day at a time. Support for starting IVF early given the impact of aging on fertility.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1b3czbl/starting_ivf_earlier_than_i_thoughtreally/", "score": 9}, {"question": "Asks about the number of egg retrieval cycles commonly needed in IVF treatments, considering financial implications.", "answer": "The number of egg retrieval cycles varies widely depending on factors such as age, egg quality, desired number of embryos, and testing preferences. Some individuals may require multiple rounds, while others find success with fewer cycles. It is best to consider personal biology and goals when planning for IVF treatments.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/owscxd/how_many_er_did_you_have_to_go_through/", "score": 5}]